Mobile:
 +64 020-4000-3464

 Email:
 pfellow@outlook.co.nz

LinkedIn: Link
GitHub: Link

Portfolio: <u>pfellow.me</u>

# **Career Objective**

Seeking an internship or a graduate position to apply my skills and expertise as a professional web developer. Programming is more than a skill – it's a hobby and a source of continuous self-development for me. I enjoy staying up to date with the latest advancements in web development and finding solutions to complex challenges. Thanks to my IT and business background as a project coordinator and business analyst, I can bridge the gap between technical expertise and business needs.

# **Skills Summary**

#### Web Development.

Skilled in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Next.js and database and cloud (AWS) technologies, with hands-on experience in creating dynamic and responsive web applications.

# **Business Analysis and Documentation.**

Skilled in analysing business requirements (I took part in several IT projects as a business analyst), gathering stakeholder needs, and translating them into comprehensive project documentation.

### Software Testing.

Experienced in implementing testing strategies, creating test scenarios and test cases, executing manual functional and regression tests, locating bugs, and creating bug reports to ensure the quality and reliability of software. Familiar with various TMSs and tools for test automation, such as Jest, Cypress, Mocha+Chai+Sinon.

#### Teamwork

Adept at collaborating with cross-functional teams, including developers, designers, and stakeholders, to achieve project objectives. Possess strong interpersonal and communication skills. I have several successful IT projects launched.

### Self-development.

Committed to continuous learning and professional growth, consistently staying updated with the latest industry trends and best practices. Proactive in seeking new opportunities to enhance skills and expand knowledge.

# **Experience Summary**

IT Project Coordinator - Velvetech July 2021 – March 2023

Technical Project Coordinator - Avtomatika-Servis

December 2020 – July 2021

Senior Business Analyst / Business Analyst - Delovye Linii

April 2016 – December 2020

Senior Logistics Specialist, Logistics Specialist - Delovye Linii, DL-Trans

September 2010 – April 2016

#### Education

### Qualifications

**Economic Manager** Economics and Construction Company Management

Vologda State Technical University, Russia 2008

Master of IT Whitireia New Zealand (Te Pūkenga) 2023

#### **Professional Development**

**Advanced training:** Project management and enterprise business processes

St. Petersburg State University of Economics 2016

Postgraduate course: Intelligent Systems (Machine Learning)

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University 2022

#### **Technical Skills**

### HTML, CSS, UI libraries

- \* Proficient in creating structured and visually appealing web pages using HTML and CSS, ensuring a seamless user experience and responsive design across different devices.
- \* Experienced in utilising CSS (such as SASS and LESS) preprocessors and libraries (such as Tailwind, Bootstrap, Material UI, Radix) to enhance the styling and layout of web applications.

#### **JavaScript**

\* Skilled in JavaScript programming, leveraging its powerful features and functionalities to create interactive and dynamic web applications.

# React.js

- \* Experienced in building modern and scalable user interfaces using React.js and related libraries such as Redux.
- \* Skilled in working with React components, managing state, and utilising React Router for efficient client-side routing.
- \* Familiar with testing React applications with Jest.

#### Node.js + Express.js

- \* Capable of building server-side applications, creating RESTful and GraphQL APIs, and handling server-side logic with Node.js, Express.js, or Next.js
- \* Familiar with using Typescript.

#### SQL, NoSQL Databases

- \* Skilled in working with SQL databases (mostly, MySQL), to design, guery, and manage relational databases.
- \* Proficient in utilising NoSQL databases (mostly, MongoDB), leveraging their flexibility and scalability for data storage and retrieval.

#### **Cloud Computing (AWS)**

- \* Knowledgeable in cloud computing concepts and experienced in working with Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- \* Experienced in deploying and managing web applications on AWS, utilising services like EC2, S3, and RDS for scalable and reliable cloud infrastructure.

# Other languages I have experience in: PHP, Python

Other skills: Project Management: Jira, Confluence, MS Project, Gantt Charts

Business analysis: BPMN, User Stories, Use case Modelling SWOT and PESTLE Techniques, MS Visio Software testing: Jest, Mocha+Chai+Sinon, Cypress, Selenium, Testrail, Test suits/cases, Bug reporting

# **Detailed Experience**

# IT Project Coordinator – Velvetech

July 2021 - March 2023

- \* Participation in various IT projects as a project coordinator, business analyst, and software tester (the role depends on the project) at all stages of the project life cycle.
- \* Development of a website (using Wix.com) for a legal company.
- \* Coordination and organising of three teams of developers.
- \* Interaction and meetings with clients and product owners, organising effective communication between team members.
- \* Definition of the scope of projects and assessment of their costs.
- \* Controlling changes, risks, and open issues in projects.
- \* Preparation of regular project reports.

# **Technical Project Coordinator -** Avtomatika-Servis

December 2020 - July 2021

- \* Technical project coordination of two complex software development projects (with a development team of more than 30 people).
- \* Formalisation of business processes and functional requirements, including the evaluation of their costs.
- \* Preparation and updating of project documentation.
- \* Organisation of effective communications between stakeholders, analysts, developers, and other departments.

# Business Analyst - Delovye Linii

**April 2016 – December 2020** 

- \* Business analysis for developing corporate information systems for operational, financial, and managerial accounting of transport and logistics companies (100 or more users) with integration with other information systems.
- \* Engineering and reengineering transport and logistics business processes.
- \* Organisation of business support (documentary and contractual support, reporting, interaction with suppliers, and IT companies).
- \* Implementation of electronic document management.

- \* Participation in IT projects (both Waterfall and Agile) as a business analyst, project coordinator, and product owner.
- \* Participation in the development and testing processes of new and existing solutions.

#### Senior Logistics Specialist, Logistics Specialist - Delovye Linii, DL-Trans

June 2012 - April 2016

- \* Participation in projects to create a vehicle queue management system in distribution centres, the creation of LTL transportation management systems, and the production schedule.
- \* Interaction with the customer service department, and trucking enterprises.
- \* Routing a fleet of assigned vehicles.
- \* Controlling movements and monitoring the performance of vehicles.
- \* Informing drivers about assignments. Liaising with the customer service department and the transport department.

# **Project Experience**

The most exciting projects for me were:

# **URL Shortener (https://ogo.gl)**

My role in the project: Developer

This is my personal (hobby) project – a web service for shortening URL links. I launched it in 2018 and since then thousands of people used it. In addition to several options for shortening URLs, this service provides various statistics on clicks. I am refactoring it currently by changing the development framework to Next.js and the database to MongoDB.

# Personal portfolio website (https://pfellow.me)

My role in the project: Developer

React.js -based one-page responsive portfolio website, containing two 3d models, smooth animations and modern elements.

# Web application for repair technicians of one of the largest American reverse logistics companies

My role in the project: Business analyst, software tester

The goal of this project was to provide a module that makes automated decisions on what products (mostly, electronics) should get repaired based on data collected throughout the repair and harvesting of spare parts processes. The web interface provides the opportunity to repair technicians to mimic the real repair process and record all the related events.

### Web platform for a legal and risk management company

My role in the project: Business analyst, developer (Wix)

An online platform/database where all incident, medical record, and claim-related information can be easily entered by numerous medical facilities around the USA and simultaneously and instantaneously shared and accessed by all necessary parties.

#### B2B Wholesale Marketplace for one of the largest American electronics resellers

My role in the project: Project Coordinator

The website empowers customers with the tools they need for a premium wholesale buying and selling experience. It is the first platform to allow mixing and matching products, making intelligent buying decisions based on sales history data, and taking advantage of volume discounts.

### **Personal and Interests**

I am patient, attentive to details, and a good team player in agile environments, though don't mind working alone if needed. I believe all conflicts can be solved (or even prevented) through communication.

I love spending my spare time swimming and hiking. I am also into playing computer, console and board games, reading and listening to science fiction books, watching Si-Fi tv shows and socialising with my friends.

I'm keen on travelling and exploring new places across the globe, and, of course, honing my web development skills.

# References

Gregory Entin CTO of Velvetech, LLC

g.entin@velvetech.dev

Gregory was my manager at Velvetech.

Andrey Ilyin Director of the Transport and Logistics Services Providers Department, Delovie Linii

Andrey.Ilin@getcargo.ru

Andrey was my manager at Delovye Linii